NICHOLAS DeCHANT

Bellevue, Washington · (425) 922-1585 · dchant@uw.edu · in/NicholasDeChant · nickdec.github.io

A skilled Data Analyst with solid analytical experience and 5+ years working as a customer service and hospitality professional. Currently a Loyalty Analyst for PACCAR Parts division. Areas of expertise include handling multiple projects and priorities, interpreting data, and reporting findings with Tableau to present insight for decision making.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Sr. Retail Promotions Analyst, PACCAR Parts

March 2021 - Current

- Develop advanced data analytics tools for reporting customer and dealer loyalty metrics.
 - Query Snowflake database to gather loyalty data and develop dashboards for use by Paccar on Tableau Server.
 - Designed popular YTD/PYTD performance Tableau dashboards for Membership Signups and Redemption Summaries, as well as over 110+ workbooks, 65 projects+ on Tableau Server applying advanced concepts: context filtering/Level of Detail calculations to create accurate and dependable reporting for company use.
- Provide expertise on the loyalty program and present information to internal and external clients.
 - Conduct monthly WebEx seminars for Loyalty program updates to Kenworth and Peterbilt dealers.
 - Provide training for Parts and Sales Managers on how to utilize the loyalty program and increase sales.
- Analyze and solve technical business and customer issues within the loyalty system.
 - Assist dealers with Loyalty issues, coupon errors on business systems/eCommerce, and loyalty reporting.
 - Solve and troubleshoot issues across multiple technologies and systems (eCommerce, DBS, Loyalty app).
- Coordinate and assist integrating dealer business systems for embedded customer loyalty.
 - Consult with notably KARMAK, CDK, and DSI to ensure Loyalty capability and support customer inquiries.

Guest Services Associate, Hilton

June 2017 – April 2020

- Create reservations, check-in guests, and ensure all guests requests are achieved accordingly.
- Arrange transportation services for guests to local businesses, restaurants, and airport.
- Maintain top tier customer service and a high level of professionalism in a team environment.

Support Manager, DCS Inc.

March 2015 - January 2017

- Assisted with Close-Range Photogrammetry workshops, provided by DCS at customer's facilities.
- Trained clients with photogrammetric software and provided maintenance services.
- Provided software technical support to customers, and webmaster for the company website.

TECHNOLOGIES and SKILLS

Programming: SQL, Java, Python, R, PHP, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, JSON

Software: Tableau, Tableau Server, Tableau Prep, Alteryx, Snowflake, SQL Server, MongoDB Compass, Rstudio

CERTIFICATIONS

Alteryx Designer Core | Alteryx | September 2020

Tableau Desktop Specialist | Tableau Software | February 2020

Exam 98-364: Database Fundamentals | Microsoft | July 2019

EDUCATION

BA, Mathematics

Fall 2011 - Spring 2015

University of Washington

Certificate of Business Intelligence

Fall 2018 - Spring 2020

Bellevue College